Muhammad Samiullah

Software Engineer

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with 4+ years of experience crafting epic web apps in Node, React, Typescript, JavaScript, SQL & NoSql. I build immersive UI/UXs, driving user engagement and exceeding client expectations. I love using technology to solve challenging real-world problems and it reflects in my work.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer | Tkxel

April 2023 - Present, Lahore, Pakistan

- Revamped Contact module for Real Estate Dashboard, achieving an impressive 50% speed increase with enhanced UI/UX contributed to the company's 15% overall growth.
- Integrated design system for a US-based client with APIs & design tokens that resulted in 50% speed optimization and 40% higher user retention and 80% code reusability.
- Spearheaded Jest and Vitest test suites that upshot 75% faster testing and 25% more code coverage for the app.
- Succeeded software development lifecycle by implementing agile methodologies, resulting in a 40% increase in team efficiency and delivering projects 20% ahead of schedule.

Senior Frontend Engineer | Emerald Labs

July 2022 - April 2023, Lahore, Pakistan

- Oversaw design and development of 3 highly interactive web apps: 15% user retention increase with a 30% annual revenue spike. Optimized code structure and quality: 30% bug reduction, and 70% code maintainability.
- Engineered scalable DynamoDB and PostgreSQL schemas for health and dating apps, enabling user growth while maintaining optimal API performance
- Architected high-performance NodeJS APIs leveraging AWS Lambda & Amplify, resulting in faster response times and improved scalability of users.
- Outperformed sophisticated tax calculator app for multiple monthly users, and managed full-cycle design tasks within client guidelines.

Senior Software Engineer | LAAM

July 2020 - June 2022, Lahore, Pakistan

- Applied D3.js chart visualization to cut the analysis time by 50% for the Analytics team, driving a 15% sales increase.
- Implemented microservice architecture with Postgres & Javascript, building a messaging service that streamlined the order management flow.
- Evaluated tech debt prioritization, and managed legacy codebase refactoring for 30% less maintenance, 50% app performance boost.
- Coordinated with C-level executives to drive a substantial increase in profits, averaging 2M+ daily sales in just 2 years.
- Completed DevOps practices, and A/B testing for sales, resulting in a 7.5% boost in conversions.
- Mentored software engineers, contributing to overall success with effective communication and team strategy and much more.

Software Engineer | Sucsel

June 2019 - June 2020, Lahore, Pakistan

- Tailored UI/UX strategies for central e-commerce, driving a 20% visitor activity increase, and a 15% platform sales boost in 6 months.
- Promoted CMS UI by elevating SEO performance, and boosting organic search trace by 15%, while deploying 7
 Shopify E-commerce stores, contributing to a whopping 200% revenue surge.
- Earned lean tech development for high-quality software systems, exceeding client expectations while spearheading initiatives with renowned brands like Ali Xeeshan, MNR, HSY, Hussain Rehar, and Tena-Durrani.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science with a major in Computer Science (BSCS) | FCCU, A Chartered University

Lahore-Pakistan, 2019

SKILLS

Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML5, CSS3

Databases: PostgreSQL, Firebase, NoSQL, MongoDB. DynamoDB

Development Methods: Scrum, Agile, Kanban, Atomic Design, Design Patterns, Design System

Main Skills: NodeJs, Express, Apollo, REST API, Esline, Prettier, Graphql, Docker, CI/CD, ReactJs, Chakra UI,

Ant Design, Redux, Zustand, Tailwind, Styled Components, React Testing Library, Storybook,

Tanstack, AWS Amplify, AWS Lambda, AWS SES, AWS SNS, Technical SEO, Shopify, Git,

Postman, Jest, Vitest, React Testing Library, Puppeteer, Cypress, Figma, Jira,

Interest & Strengths: Communication, Management and Leadership, Global Entrepreneurship, Web Design, Growth.

Speaking Language: English Professional (C1)